<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on eddie</title>
    <link>https://edsammy.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on eddie</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edsammy.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Business School</title>
      <link>https://edsammy.github.io/blog/business-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edsammy.github.io/blog/business-school/</guid>
      <description>Why? I&amp;rsquo;ve decided I need some more thoughtfulness around business ideas. Here are some videos that constitute my business schooling:&#xA;Finding Value Proposition 2023&#xA;Harvard Innovation Lab&#xA;Michael Skok (Underscore VC, Startup Secrets)&#xA;Additional material: https://startupsecretssandbox.com&#xA;Notes:&#xA;Problem format: target customer is dissatisfied with current situation due to an unmet need we offer a product that provides them with amazing benefit MVP must serve a MV segment this allows your product to focus a single thing in the beginning trying to address too big of a market can stretch you too thing &amp;ldquo;A problem well stated is a problem half-solved&amp;rdquo; Charles Kettering (1876-1985) 186 patents 4U&amp;rsquo;s unworkable unavoidable (death, taxes, education, aging) urgent (&amp;ldquo;I need that now!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Nance Story</title>
      <link>https://edsammy.github.io/blog/the-nance-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edsammy.github.io/blog/the-nance-story/</guid>
      <description>Backstory In 2021 my sister and brother-in-law launched an NFT project called Fly Frogs1. He did the art, she wrote the code. I was working at an engineering consultancy called Very at the time doing electrical engineering and product development for clients that either had an idea they wanted to turn into a product OR to rescue them from their previous consultancy that promised they could do the same. It was a good place to work but consultancies are a tough business, maintaining a satisfied engineering work force is difficult especially with the constant reminder of what the company is charging clients vs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is the first post</title>
      <link>https://edsammy.github.io/blog/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:29:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edsammy.github.io/blog/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Getting started because its hard to get started&#xA;Reminds me of The Staunton Lick. Not sure why but it does!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
